VIKRAM SHARMA

Chantilly, VA 20152 · email | linkedin | portfolio | blog · (202) 577-6303

SUMMARY

Six years of experience in hardware development, three years of experience in software engineering. My ability to learn on-the-fly, desire to be challenged, and genuine curiosity drive me towards a like-minded team capable of providing data-driven, efficient solutions on an expedited timeline.

SKILLS

Java
Express
Javascript
REST API
Node
React
PostgreSQL
SQLite
Bash
HTML
PowerShell
Git

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PLANTARION October 2020 - Present

Part-time Front End Web Developer

- Supporting three web apps with HTML, CSS, and VueJS
- Leading weekly Scrum meetings and taking charge of the front-end team to complete big ticket items in a timely manner
- Taking charge of Plantarion WordPress blog and styling it to fit the UI of the main and event sites

SURVICE Engineering May 2020 - November 2020

Software Engineer

- Manually parsed and extracted data from 18,000+ files with scripts written in Python
- Spearheaded search engine optimization effort using MySQL, PHP, and Apache to display refined search results
- Supported development efforts on the DSIAC Azure platform through PowerShell and Azure's web interface
- Complied with Impact Level IV security STIGs while writing and maintaining code

GENERAL ASSEMBLY January 2020 - April 2020

Software Engineer Fellow

- Delivered assignments and projects on expedited timelines during 80-hour work weeks
- Pioneered a study-hall group for the class and actively led assignment discussions and pair programming sessions
- Designed and developed 20 web applications using Linux operating systems from the ground up

BLACKHAT TECHNOLOGY September 2015 - Present

Owner & Founder

- Facilitating and customizing client projects from an initial consultation to an up-and-running PC
- Offering extended support and services such as technical support, water cooling installation, and cable management
- Specializing in building crypto-currency mining computers during the crypto "boom"

PROJECTS

DSIAC/DSIMS | link June 2020 - November 2020

Customer-facing WordPress page and back-end SQL database for Technical Inquiry data processed through DSIAC
Maintained WordPress page as well as the back-end via Windows Remote Desktop

- Scripted batch file operations via PowerShell to extend returned search data in DSIMS and parse attachments
- Assisted in efforts to migrate the DSIMS Windows VM to a Linux environment for future development

PLANTARION WEBPAGE | link

June 2020 - Present

- Client and investor facing webpage built in HTML with a blog built in WordPress
 - Learning and using WordPress to develop and maintain the Plantarion blog website

Working on frequent updates to three web apps within a 3-5 day timeline per update

STOMPING GROUNDS APPLICATION | link

March 2020

E-commerce React application that allows consumers to show different styles of boots based on their preferences

- Led a team to meet the MVP standards within a 3 day timeline via Agile and GitHub
- Developed a Node API to serve jSON objects to the front end React-based application using REST routes
- Completed full CRUD functionality linked to the front-end via asynchronous functions

EDUCATION

NORTHERN VIRGINIA COMMUNITY COLLEGE, Sterling, VA

January 2017 - Present